Ramzi Daher +44 7881816740

<u>ramzi.daher@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramzi-daher-621292232

Personal profile

First year Computer science (with placement year) bachelor's undergraduate degree student at the University of Sussex. I possess very strong technical understanding, coupled with exceptional skills, in IT, Technology and computing at large, gained from my degree and past work experience. I am experienced in Java, python and hardware fixing for electronic devices/PCBs.

Education

2022 – current: Computer Science with placement year BSc (Hons), University of Sussex

Key modules include:

Semester one:

- Introduction to Multimedia
- Mathematical concepts
- programming concepts
- Introduction to Programming

Semester Two:

- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Professional Skills
- Further programming
- Introduction to Computer systems

Awards:

Global design project
 https://www.sussex.ac.uk/ei/internal/forstudents/globaldesignchallenge

Projects:

• GitHub: https://github.com/ramzidaher

2013 – 2020: International Baccalaureate Diploma (IB), Ramallah Friends School

Work experience

May 2021 – Sept 2021: Technical Support, OFFTEC Palestine, www.offtec.ps

- I was part of the team responsible of technical support for a variety of machines and banking technology systems, e.g., Diebold Nixdorf ATMs, DataCard ID and Financial solutions, Cheque clearing and sorting system and various other banking solutions.
- I also was responsible to repair and troubleshoot, both hardware and software, Acer laptops, being the only authorised Acer Service Centre in Palestine
- My tasks included daily routine jobs to handle service calls and preventive maintenance for bank's branches across Palestine and large corporations where mission critical systems were deployed by OFFTEC.

Dec 2021 – current: MeFix, https://www.facebook.com/mefixpal

- Since the beginning of COVID I was helping my neighbours with their devices, fixing their laptops, PC's, setting up their routers and many more.
- Post this I decided to turn this growing hobby of mine into a side business where I can fix laptops, printers' phones remotely utilising several software tools and applications
- This has not only been generating some pocket money for me but also is an enriching experience when I leave a good impression on my customers.

Voluntary experience

Helping the elderly community in church:

- Back home, my church would hold every month breakfast dinners for the elderly community, I would go help them set up and serve food for everyone
- Another activity that I was part of it their bingo night where, my DJ skills came in handy in setting up the sound system, choosing the rights songs and playing them

Additional skills and interests

- Photography and Videography
 (https://1drv.ms/u/s!ApP4271hd34zhKQOUPvJsWvs5gLp6Q?e=Ldc8Wx)
- DJ and Music production (https://soundcloud.com/user-551809891)
- Video Editing
- Cycling